Guide to the Senior Honor Essays of Yale Students
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Numerical, Series II
  - Senior Honor Essays
    - Weintraub, Myles R.—"The European coal and steel community; an analysis of words and deeds", 1958 (Box 32, Folder 211)
    - Weise, Steven Owen—"Lawyers for the politically unpopular", 1971 (Box 32, Folder 212)
    - Weston, Theodore, II—"Alternatives facing Rumanian foreign policy", 1939 (Box 32, Folder 213)
    - White, William Gardner—"Government regulation of passenger air transport since 1938", 1942 (Box 32, Folder 214)
    - Wiener, Alexander L., Jr.—"The foreign relations of the United States with the royal kingdom of Laos", 1959 (Box 33, Folder 215)
    - Will, Henry G.—"The politics of centralization: a case study of legislation in Connecticut", 1962 (Box 33, Folder 216)
    - Winger, Michael—"Alienation and politics. The way workers think about their jobs and the way they think about the political system", 1967 (Box 33, Folder 217)
    - Winter, Ralph K., Jr.—"The Communist exploitation of the Rosenberg Case", 1957 (Box 33, Folder 218)
    - Winter, Sidney G.—"The political palatability of progress in France: a study in national income organization", 1958 (Box 33, Folder 219)
    - Winters, Wilda Glasgow—"Black mothers in urban schools: a study of participation and alienation", 1975 (Box 33, Folder 220)
    - Woocher, Jonathan S.—"Ideology and congress: a perspective and analysis", 1968 (Box 33, Folder 221)
    - Youngwood, Alfred D.—"Energy in the executive; a study of the ebb and flow of power of two-term presidents of the United States during the twentieth century", 1959 (Box 34, Folder 222)
    - Ziebarth, Karl—"The Sudan: imperialism and independence, 1920-1956", 1959 (Box 34, Folder 223)
    - Zimmer, Richard A.—"The senate committee on foreign relations: the challenge of integration", 1966 (Box 34, Folder 224)
    - Zucker, Jeffrey P.—"The reapportionment revolution?", 1968 (Box 34, Folder 225)
    - Michael, Peter K.—"The Western big-game frontier", 1978 (Box 34, Folder 226)
    - Jump, Alice K.—"Redemption through aridity: William Smythe and the irrigation crusade", 1978 (Box 34, Folder 227)
  - Social Science Senior Essays (Add. 7/79)
    - Achs, Robert—"The subject as his own researcher: an attempt at a method", 1971 (Box 34, Folder 228)
    - Adelberg, Robert—"'The homosexual' as deviant: an inquiry into the history, causes and processes of anti-homosexualism; with special reference to America", 1970 (Box 34, Folder 229)
    - Allison, M. Katherine—"Perspectives on young people", 1971 (Box 35, Folder 230)
    - Bemis, Stephen—"The individual in a mass-culture society: the role of roles", 1969 (Box 35, Folder 231)
    - Bodinger, Cristina—"Mexico-1890-1910: a socio-economic overview focusing on the role of ideas, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 232)
    - Brawer, Barney—"Two concepts of ability, testing, grouping, the rich, the poor, the history of the schools, and some relationships among the above", [1969] (Box 35, Folder 233)
    - Brisker, Stephen Edward—"The historical development of Black radio programming… at Yale University…", 1971 (Box 35, Folder 234)
    - Burstein, Alan N.—"Population forecasting in the United States between 1920 and 1950", 1970 (Box 35, Folder 235)
    - Coe, Andrew—"Football coaching in the Ivy League: patterns and problems", [1970] (Box 35, Folder 236)
    - Cohen, Henry—"Placentia", 1971 (Box 35, Folder 237)
    - Corhan, Ken—"Wooster Square: an invitation into community", 1970 (Box 35, Folder 238)
    - Cottle, M.G.—"Advertising: another view", [1970] (Box 35, Folder 239)
    - Davis, Martin J.—"Yale Senior Societies: a study of change in institutionalized small groups", 1970 (Box 35, Folder 240)
    - Davis, Smith W.—"The Black self-image: the need for perspective", 1970 (Box 35, Folder 241)
    - DeChellis, Peter—"Television and social change: a theoretical insight", [1970] (Box 35, Folder 242)
    - DeFrancesco, Mark—"Third District study: the 1970 Congressional race", 1971 (Box 36, Folder 243)
    - Deveaux, Jon—"Dreams, the disadvantaged, and a model educational system", 1970 (Box 36, Folder 244)
    - Dillon, Stephen D.—"The Mexican American and the American educational system: toward a theory of minority group education", 1971 (Box 36, Folder 245)
    - Disco, Cornelis—"Values in society: an analysis of three theoretical perspectives", 1969 (Box 36, Folder 246)
    - Dowling, Brian—"A look at interracial relations in the Ivy League", [1969] (Box 36, Folder 247)
    - Eifler, Deborah—"Images of the feminine: fifty years of Ladies Home Journal advertising defines the American woman", 1971 (Box 36, Folder 248)
    - Esposito, Donna—"The effects of prosocial television on the preschool child's socialization into society", 1977 (Box 36, Folder 249)
    - Fagan, Joan—"Social factors influencing the recognition of Black art", 1975 (Box 36, Folder 250)
    - Fasold, E.J.—"A case study of interpersonal behavior in a group of factory workers", [1971] (Box 36, Folder 251)
    - [Flores, Enrique]—[Paper on Chicanos and S.A.T.s], [1977]. (Box 36, Folder 252)
    - Galvin, Peter D.—"Social science and policy making: Brown v. Board of Education", 1970 (Box 36, Folder 253)
    - Goldin, Stephen J.—"Smack in the ghetto: the American dream? An adaptive response to a destructive society", 1971 (Box 36, Folder 254)
    - Goodman, Anne—"Women's liberation and its implications for the family structure", 1970 (Box 36, Folder 255)
    - Grande, Timothy—"Capitalism and the entrepreneur in late nineteenth century America", 1978 (Box 37, Folder 256)
    - Griggs, Robert W.—"The sociology of knowledge and its applicability to Wayward Puritans by Kai T. Erikson", 1969 (Box 37, Folder 257)
    - Guercia, Carol—"The effects of the legalization of abortion in the State of New York", 1971 (Box 37, Folder 258)
    - Harris, Alan Morse—"The movement: why it began and grew in modern American society", 1971 (Box 37, Folder 259)
    - Harris, Wiley L.—"An analysis of the business consequences of small group relations", 1970 (Box 37, Folder 260)
    - Hassett, Mark J.—"Budgetary decision-making among medical doctors and hospital administrators at Yale-New Haven Hospital", 1971 (Box 37, Folder 261)
    - Jackson, Melvin A.—"Obscenity and pornography: a socio-theoretical observation", 1971 (Box 37, Folder 262)
    - Jampol, Robert Roy—"Alienation: a sociological perspective", [1971] (Box 37, Folder 263)
    - Jean, Rodney—"Example and reward in learning", [1971] (Box 37, Folder 264)
    - Kane, Kevin—"An exploratory study into the structure and process of success in the music industry", 1976 (Box 37, Folder 265)
    - Kennedy, Katherine—"The women's movement in New Haven: who is involved and why", 1977 (Box 37, Folder 266)
    - Kommerstad, Bryce—"Social values survey", 1971 (Box 37, Folder 267)
    - Kusterer, Ken—"Political attitudes in a White, working class neighborhood", 1969 (Box 37, Folder 268)
    - Lee, Daniel Gerard, Jr.—"The founders and the executives: a sociological study of the boarding school headmastership", 1971 (Box 37, Folder 269)
    - Lieb, Peter—"The struggle of traditions: Boss Tweed and the immigrant peasant in a world of Yankee indignation", 1978 (Box 37, Folder 270)
    - Lu, James C.—"Chinese Americans: history and analysis of three immigrant groups", 1977 (Box 38, Folder 271)
    - McCarthy, Tim—"The emerging social form of religion: methodological problems from a scientific perspective", 1978 (Box 38, Folder 272)
    - McManus, F. Benjamin—"The total success of women athletes at Yale: social planning and subculture hypotheses", [1978] (Box 38, Folder 273)
    - Macmurdo, Bruce—"Playground and high school basketball in New Haven", 1971 (Box 38, Folder 274)
    - Miller, Mathew T.—"Special expertise, duty, and military professionalism: a dynamic model", 1978 (Box 38, Folder 275)
    - Newmyer, Arthur G., III—"Discharge from a mental hospital: the Yale Psychiatric Institute discharge groups", 1971 (Box 38, Folder 276)
    - Ngau, Timothy—"Images of the future: idio-social perspectives on what's to come", 1975 (Box 38, Folder 277)
    - Parker, Gregory K.—"Social control and sexuality", 1971 (Box 38, Folder 278)
    - Perry, Stephen Craig—"Runaways: on youth in society", 1971 (Box 38, Folder 279)
    - Pers, Jessica S.—"The role of the teacher in an unstructured educational environment: faculty communication and decision-making at the high school in the community", 1971 (Box 38, Folder 280)
    - Popper, Andrew J.—"An essay on the understanding of urban culture", 1969 (Box 38, Folder 281)
    - Robinson, Geoffrey A.—"Theoretical problems and issues in the study of social conflict: a study with attention to Ralf Dahrendorf's theory of class conflict", 1971 (Box 38, Folder 282)
    - Rosenberg, Eric—"The problems of community control: an analysis of the community control plans of the Sound View-Throgs Neck Community Mental Health Center", 1970 (Box 38, Folder 283)
    - Rothman, Debbie—"Women at Yale: II", 1971 (Box 39, Folder 284)
    - Rubottom, Alan E.—"PULSA/Research Association in the Arts: the social consequences of the new media", [1969?] (Box 39, Folder 285)
    - Sawyer, Annita P.—"Factors contributing to dysfunctional problem-solving behavior in children", 1971 (Box 39, Folder 286)
    - Sawyer, William B.—Fundamental properties of social change", 1969 (Box 39, Folder 287)
    - Schachtel, Roger—"Film: the perils of a mass art in organizational development and societal function", 1971 (Box 39, Folder 288)
    - Schmidt, Herbert Joachin—"Breaking the circle", 1970 (Box 39, Folder 289)
    - Schnitt, Jerome M.—"The mental hospital system: its problems and failings", 1969 (Box 40, Folder 290)
    - Scott, Andrew C.—"A study of group judgements and values related to the sociology of deviance and social structure", [1969] (Box 40, Folder 291)
    - Shafton, Ben—"The Socialist Party of America in New York City: portrait and demise of a radical party", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 292)
    - Smith, Herb—"The social heterogeneity of the European Left: ideology versus electoral success", 1977 (Box 40, Folder 293)
    - Switzler, C. Brant—"A social history of tobacco", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 294)
    - Talan, Jeffrey S.—"Social change in the Winhall Township area of Vermont", 1971 (Box 40, Folder 295)
    - Tomassi, Eric—"Radicalizing the family: experiment and change in micro-communities", 1971 (Box 40, Folder 296)
    - Waller, Thurston J.—"Ethnomethological research: perception: the reflexivity of a given phenomenon", 1977 (Box 40, Folder 297)
    - Weissman, Paul J.—"Karl Marx and the international economic crisis", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 298)
    - West, Stephen M.—"Rituals of opposition: notes on counter cultural events", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 299)
    - Whitridge, David—"Discipline and authority in the public schools", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 300)
    - Woods, William C.—"Social decision making and the conservation of a natural resource (examined: the Redwood National Park)", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 301)
  - Senior Honors Essays
    - Cowell, Eugene Francis, III—"To Change Chinatown: Reform in San Francisco's Chinese quarter 1882-1906", [1979] (Box 40, Folder 302)